《越狱》第四季 第十三集
Prison.Break.S04E13
《越狱》  前情提要
Previousely On Prison Break.
这才是"锡拉"
This is Sylly
你们是出不去的
You are not even close to get out of here
-爸爸  是我  -丽莎
Dad, it's me.  Lisa
我在枪口上  是唐克雷蒂
I'm at gun point It's Tancredit
她说  你要是不让迈克尔和其他人
She says if you don't,let Michael and the others
带着"锡拉"离开  她就杀了我
leave with Scylla, she'll kill me.
别动
Don't!
我要走了
I'm leaving.
不  怀特先生
No, Mr. White!
转过去
Turn around!
轻点  甜心
Gentle now, sugar.
我是米里亚姆・贺尔兹探员  甜心
That's Special Agent Miriam Holtz to you, sugar.
我们拿到了
We have it!
他们拿到了
They got it.
我没想到 你能查到这么深
I never thought you'd make it this far.
我错了
I was wrong.
怎样
What now?
这是你们的迁移文件
This is all your transfer paperwork.
我得尽快赶到达洛斯那边去
I need to get to Dallow, ASAP.
格雷琴呢
What happened to Gretchen?
她跑了
She got away.
赛尔夫
Self.
赛尔夫[又意:自私鬼]
他骗了我们
He screwed us.
赛尔夫不能这么做
Self can't do that.
他是政府人员  想干什么都行
He's government. He can do what he pleases.
车一定会来的
The vans are coming.
肯定是耽误了
They're just late.
他不会回来了
He ain't coming back!
你也不确定  林肯  他们会来的
You don't know that, Linc! They're coming!
我们现在怎么办
What do we do now?
给国安局打电话  看他们对赛尔夫了解多少
Call Homeland. See how much they know about Self.
斯坦顿
Stanton.
贺勃  是斯科菲尔德和布伦斯
Herb, it was Scofield and Burrows.
你在议员的办公室吗
Are you at the Senator's office?
我中枪了
I think I'm shot!
I'm shot!
米里亚姆也死了  你听见吗
Miriam's gone, okay?
你在什么地方
What's your position?
这整个行动 你说的是对的
You were right about this whole operation.
不要  布伦斯  布伦斯
No. Burrows, Burrows!
唐
Don.
不妙
No!
我要找格雷琴 你会帮我吗
I need to find Gretchen. You gonna help me?
否则  我让你脸上开花
Or you gonna make me shoot you in the face?
帮[又意:救命]
Help.
国土安全局
Department of Homeland Security.
我找唐・赛尔夫的上司  谢谢
I'd like to talk to Don Self's superior, please.
请稍等
One moment, please.
我们把价值一亿的东西 就这么拱手送给这家伙了
We gave this guy something worth $100 million.
他是国安局的吗  我们看过他的徽章吗
Is he even with Homeland? Did we see a badge?
他给了我们枪  用C-130运输机送我们过来
We were given guns and flown out on a C-130.
-他肯定不是车管局的 -这也不代表他是合法的
He didn't work for the DMV. That doesn't make him the law.
不  不能
No, it don't.
要是国安局从一开始就参与了呢
What if Homeland was in on this from the beginning?
我是贺勃・斯坦顿  你是谁
This is Herb Stanton. Who is this?
喂
Hello?
我搞不清赛尔夫是怎么设的局
The way Self played this, I don't know.
他一直让自己置身事外
He kept himself too insulated.
这就是为什么 需要政府授权时
That's why, that's why he hesitated with official authorizations
他总是犹豫 他总是说  这是为了防止
on behalf of our mission. He kept saying it was because he didn't want
"公司"发现  而实际上
the Company to find out. In actuality,
他是不想让人发现他的诡计
it's because he didn't want to get caught,
狗娘养的
the son of a bitch!
他部署周密 让我们去承担责任
He kept the circle tight. Left the rest of us holding the bag.
如果国安局知道我们在哪 他们迟早会来抓我们
If Homeland knows where we're at. Sooner or later they're coming for us.
让他们来吧 我们又没做错什么  我们有协议的
Let them come. we didn't do anything wrong. We have deals.
不  我们只有白纸  赛尔夫留给我们的
No, we have paper. That's what Self left us.
我们只有这些
That's what we have.
我们得离开这里
We gotta get out of here.
我们不能走  迈克尔需要做手术
We can't leave. Michael needs surgery.
我说的不是逃跑
I'm not talking about running.
我说的是活命
I'm talking about surviving.
我想要的是目睹"公司"土崩瓦解
What I want is to see the Company burned to the ground
而你  锒铛入狱
and you in prison.
这是我们干的  我们干的
We did this to you. We did this to you.
他们正在楼下等你  长官
They're ready for you downstairs, sir.
今天是我们所有努力的关键时刻
Today marks a critical juncture in our endeavor.
有没有"锡拉"的蛛丝马迹
Do we have a bead on Scylla yet?
我们的安全和未来  均命悬一线
Our security, our future stands at a great precipice.
到底有还是没有  乔纳森
It's a yes-or-no question, Jonathan.
我们不想听你自言自语
And we don't need a soliloquy.
霍华德  你去我办公室等我
Howard, why don't you wait in my office?
不  我来此 是确保这次行动不会再出差错
No. I'm in here making sure this operation isn't fumbled as well.
马上出去
Out... now.
你有什么计划  乔纳森
What's your plan, Jonathan?
我们来不就是为了这个吗
That's what we're all here for, right?
你不听我们的箴言 执意转移"锡拉"  如今弄巧成拙
You tried to move Scylla over our better judgment, and it backfired,
就认了吧
so spill it.
还有其他问题吗
Any further questions?
很好
Very well.
你们都知道自己的任务了
You have your assignments.
竭尽所能  今天就把"锡拉"找回来
Access your assets and retrieve Scylla today.
赛尔夫探员  过去几个月里
Yeah, well, a lot of people that believed in me
很多相信我的人 现在都死了
in the last few months, Agent Self, not all of them are alive today.
我不明白这句话
I can't shake that line.
"走为上策"
"All that avails is flight."
起来
Come on.
给  拿着
Here, take that.
莎拉是对的  我们得送你去医院
Sara's right. We need to get you to a hospital now.
我们就差那么一点 就那么一点
We were so close to the finish line. So close.
我知道  我明白
Yeah, I know, I know, I know.
我昨天给LJ打了电话 告诉他一切都接近尾声了
Listen, I, uh, I spoke to LJ yesterday. Told him this was almost over.
我要对我儿子信守诺言
I'm keeping my word to my son, Michael.
我早该发现这个阴谋
I should have seen this coming.
不  这不是任何人的错 是赛尔夫耍了我们
No, no, it's no one's fault. Self played all of us.
我们得离开这里 这是我们最后的选择
We gotta get out of here. This is our last option.
好的
Yeah.
-查看楼上  -安全
Take upstairs.Clear.
安全
It's clear.
现在知道我们的处境了
Now we know where we stand.
走吧
Let's go.
喂
Hello.
迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield.
是的
Yes.
我是贺勃・斯坦顿  国土安全局的
Herb Stanton, Department of Homeland Security.
我们想谈谈
We want to talk.
你们能不能回仓库
Can you please come back to the warehouse?
没问题  但首先得给我们一些保障
All right, but first we're gonna need some assurances.
你指什么
What kind of assurances?
我们遵守了我们的诺言
Look, we held up our end of the deal,
所以  我们要你 履行协议里的条件
so we're gonna need you to honor the terms of our agreements.
那我得重新看一下那些条件
Well, I'd have to take another look at those terms,
但我确定里面不包括偷走"锡拉"
but I'm fairly certain it didn't include stealing Scylla
和冷血杀害两名联邦探员
or killing two federal agents in cold blood.
你这话是什么意思
What are you talking about?
我给你们准备了 一些新的条件
Here are the new terms I'm prepared to offer.
回来  自首
Come back, turn yourselves in...
等等  是赛尔夫算计了我们
Wait a minute! Self set us up!
否则 我会追捕你们到天涯海角
Don't, and I'll hunt you down like animals.
我们照他们说的做了
We did what they said.
我不想再背捏造的谋杀罪了
I ain't going down on some trumped-up murder charge.
赛尔夫把两起谋杀案扣到我们头上
Self pinned two murders on us.
你在干嘛  林肯
What are you doing, Linc?
如果国安局的人来了 我们能摆平
If Homeland Security comes... Then we'll handle it.
你要知道 总有划清界线的限度
You know what? There's gotta be a point where you draw the line.
现在就是时候了
Now's the time to draw that line.
林肯  别傻了  你对付不了整个国安局的
Linc,don't be stupid. You can't fight off all of Homeland.
听政府的鬼话才是最傻的
Stupid is listening to the government.
我可不想再回死囚区了
I ain't going back to death row,Doc.
我们还能遵守诺言
We can still hold onto our deals.
只要揪出赛尔夫  证明他拿了"锡拉"
All we have to do is flush Self out, prove he has Scylla.
我们怎么做呢
How are we gonna do that, huh?
我们得想个新策略
We have to devise another strategy.
我们应该想个计划
We should start devising a plan
把我们送出墨西哥边境几英里外
that can get us a hundred miles across the Mexican border.
那才是我们该做的
That's what we should do.
我表弟裴迪可以接应我们
My cousin Petey can hook us up.
我们不会逃跑
We're not running.
我们不能逃跑
We can't.
没有斯科菲尔德  布伦斯和马宏的消息
Negative on Scofield, Burrows and Mahone.
目录区认为赛尔夫可能用了捕捉器 掩盖了手机信号
TDZ think that Self may be using a bakergrip to mask his cell phone signal.
在国安局周围安排一支战略队伍
Place a tactical team around Homeland.
如果赛尔夫或其他那些混蛋出现
If Self or any of those other bastards show up,
确保他们不能靠近大楼
make damn well sure they don't get near the building.
我不能回到进出汽车旅馆的生活
I can't go back to living in and out of motels,
无时无刻担惊受怕
Constantly looking over my shoulder.
计划照旧  我们要搞垮公司 善始善终
Nothing changes. We take down the Company. We finish what we started.
你在给谁打电话
Who are you calling?
医生
A doctor.
莎拉  现在不是时候
Sara, not now.
那该什么时候
When?
听着
Whoa-whoa-whoa, listen.
科尔・普发  市中心知名企业
Cole Pfeiffer, an employee of GATE,
伽特公司的一名职员 和一名身份不明的女同伙
a downtown wellness organization, and his yet-unidentified- female accomplice
警方提供素描图缉拿
both seen here in police sketches.
还有他们 格雷琴 巴格维尔
And them. Gretchen? Bagwell?
让我们在交通部的人 监控从圣地亚哥到海岸地区的
Have our people at DOT monitor every traffic camera
所有交通摄像
from San Diego to the Bay Area.
我不敢相信你居然开枪打死了他
I can't believe you shot him.
适时割除癌变的肢体 以保全身体其他部位
Knowing when to sever a cancerous limb to preserve the rest of the body.
他可是你最信任的顾问和知己
He was one of your most trusted advisors and confidant.
我让你参与进来时
When I brought you in
就告诉过你  持卡人需肩负一定责任
I told you that a cardholder has certain responsibilities.
如果你无法 胜任我们的工作 现在就能告诉我
If you can't handle what we're doing here, it's time you let me know.
总裁格雷戈里・怀特 在对峙中被杀
CEO Gregory White  who was shot and killed in the standoff.
警方正在调查凶手的动机 是复仇还是抢劫
Police are trying to determine whether revenge or robbery was the motive.
科尔・普发是近期
Cole Pfeiffer was a recent addition...
看来不只我们被捉弄了
Maybe we weren't the only ones left hanging, huh?
如果要揪出赛尔夫 你觉得他会怎么甩手"锡拉"
If we're gonna flush Self out, how do you think he intended to unload Scylla?
格雷琴
Gretchen.
他会卖掉它
He's got to sell it.
我要是猜错了  就说一声
Tell me when I'm getting warm.
你精心挑选了迈克尔・斯科菲尔德一伙人
You hand-picked Michael Scofield and the bunch,
花政府的银子把他们运过来
trucked them all out here on Uncle Sam's dime,
为你卖命  现在他们
to do your bidding, and now they're
成了你的所作所为的枪靶子
standing right in the crosshairs for what you did.
我真佩服你  唐  干得比蒙娜丽莎还漂亮
I gotta hand it to you Don, if that ain't the Mona Lisa.
我一直说警察比罪犯还狡猾
I always said cops are more crooked than criminals.
让我猜一猜  就为了 尝点甜头吗
Let me guess. a little, little slice of heaven, is that what it was for?
还赌债
Gambling debt?
或许你是个 研究冰糖种类的地质学家
Maybe you're a... a geologist of the rock candy variety?
用格雷琴的指纹查到的信息
The information you got from Gretchen's prints,
你确定是正确的地址吗
you sure it's the right address?
-完全正确  -很好  现在 闭嘴  否则我毙了你 懂了吗
Right as rain. Good. Now, shut up or I'm gonna shoot you. Understand me?
我
Oh, I, I...
-闭嘴  -我没有
Shut your mouth. I ain't...
-我知道什么时候  -闭嘴
-I know when... -Shut your mouth.
-闭嘴  -安静
to shut my... Be quiet.
在这个城市找个公共电话要多久时间
How long does it take to find a pay phone in this city?
他们就快回来了
They'll be back.
好了
Okay.
跟以前一样
Same deal as before.
是的
Yeah.
在接下来8小时内 不能有身体压力
No physical duress for the next eight hours.
重要的是 你需要帮助
Here's the thing. You need help.
到处奔走 追查赛尔夫是不安全的
And running around trying to track down Self isn't... safe.
只要几小时  我们就能到墨西哥
We could be in Mexico in a few hours.
那里有我信任的医生
There are doctors there that I trust.
一直以来  都是你照顾我们
And you've been taking care of all of us.
现在由我们来照顾你也是理所当然
I think it's really okay if we take care of you.
不管做不做手术
Surgery or no surgery...
不把那些人搞垮
I'm never gonna be able to live with myself
我是无法独自苟存的 就这么简单
unless I find a way to take these people down. It's that simple,
我明白
and, uh... I get it.
我不强求你感同身受
I'm not gonna demand that you feel the same way.
告诉你  我们不能相信任何人
I'm telling you, we can't trust anyone.
政府  执法机关
government, law enforcement...
-所以我们才应该想办法离开这里  -不行
Which is all the more reason we should consider getting out of here. No.
我们要了结这事
We deal with this now.
我也想把他揪出来
I want this guy as much as you do,
但我们都自身难保
but we're scrambling here.
我不知道赛尔夫策划了多久
I mean, I don't know how long Self has been planning
就表面看来  简直天衣无缝
this thing and from the looks of it, it's pretty air-tight.
格雷琴
Gretchen.
我希望你打电话是告诉我"锡拉"的下落  林肯
I hope you're calling me to tell me where Scylla is, Lincoln.
你不知道吗
You don't know?
我不知道
I don't know.
怎么回事
What's going on?
赛尔夫出卖了我们  他拿走了"锡拉"
Self double-crossed us and he took Scylla.
你知道他可能在哪吗
You know where he could be?
如果我是赛尔夫  我会找个新买家
If I'm Self, I'm looking for a new buyer.
新买家
A new buyer?
告诉你
You know what?
你要是耍我 我就把你劈成两半
If you're playing me, I'm gonna split you in half.
我和你们一样想找出他
I want him just as badly as you do.
你们在哪  我去找你们
Where are you? I'm coming to you.
希望公园  一小时后见
Grand Hope Park. One hour.
什么事
What?
姐姐
Sis.
是 艾米丽  她 出事了
It's... Emily. She's, um... been in an accident.
我要你告诉用枪指着你的人
I want you to tell whoever's got that gun pointed at you
长个胆子再听电话
to grow a set and get on the phone.
她要和你谈
She wants to talk to you.
别来无恙  格雷琴
What's up, Gretchen?
该回家了
Time to come home now.
我们真的要相信那个婊子吗
Are we really gonna keep trusting that bitch?
格雷琴和帝博格 当时拿着枪等在伽特啊  伙计们
Gretchen and T-Bag, Were waiting at GATE with machine guns, guys.
你以为他们想提供后援吗
You think they just wanted to provide cover?
这个女人唯利是图
This chick's a mercenary.
她为达目的可以不择手段
She'll do whatever it takes to get what she wants,
目前我们只是碰巧想要同一样东西
and right now we just happen to want the same thing.
我们要有所防备
We are taking precautions, but...
但不管怎样  格雷琴
one way or the other, Gretchen's
能帮我们找到赛尔夫  而现在 这才是最重要的
gonna get us to Self, and right now... ...that is all that matters.
我们根本没机会
We don't stand a chance.
我们的照片还没有在电视上公开
Our photos aren't plastered all over the TV.
国安局没有公开
Homeland's keeping it in-house.
我们还有机会
We have a chance.
参议员
Senator?
贺勃
Herb.
我们本着好意开展这次行动
We sponsored this operaton with the best of intentions,
但我们采取的秘密方式
but the secretive manner in which we've handled it
我担心会弄巧成拙
I now fear is working against us.
怎么说
How so?
我们正在搜捕罪犯
We're in the middle of a manhunt,
但只有你 和几个特工出动
and it's just you and a couple of agents out there trying to rein in these cons.
这太疯狂了
It's madness.
我们最初开展的计划 没有成功
What we initally sponsored... didn't pan out.
但不意味着一发不可收拾
That doesn't mean that the boat is taking on water.
没有人知道
No one knows.
以后也不会有人知道
That's the way it's going to stay.
进来
Come in!
下午好
Good afternoon.
理查德・苏特  美国联邦执法局
Richard Sooter, US Marshals Service.
我奉副局长伊斯玛之命 彻查斯科菲尔德
I've been sent at the request of Deputy Director Esmar to get to the bottom
和布伦斯的案件
of the Scofield/Burrows Supermax story
一次查清
once and for all.
我希望你们能帮忙
I'm hoping you gentlemen can help.
各位  如果有 难言之隐  但说无妨
Guys, if there's a reason you're keeping secrets... just fill me in here.
我能帮忙
I canhelp.
你的承受力如何
How strong is your stomach?
很强
Very.
贺勃・斯坦顿
Herb... Stanton.
他和唐・赛尔夫合作
He's working with Donald Self.
我们拿到了今天所有国安局的电话记录
We got a record of all incoming and outgoing calls from Homeland today.
斯坦顿接到一个大概有一分钟的电话
Stanton received a call lasting approximately one minute
但来电人不明 我们无法确认此人身份
that was connected to no one. No one we could identify.
赛尔夫打的电话
Self's phone.
交管局从一个道路摄像头里 发现了格雷琴
D.O.T. has a positive ID on Gretchen from a traffic cam.
她还在洛杉矶
She's still in Los Angeles.
克里斯从约翰内斯堡打电话过来 想知道最新消息
Chris is on the phone from Johannesburg, looking for an update.
我稍后回电话
I'll call back.
现在  关于这位斯坦顿先生
Now, about this Mr. Stanton...
阿历克斯  情况如何
Alex, how are you doing?
还没有格雷琴的迹象
No sign of Gretchen yet.
林肯
Linc?
没有格雷琴的迹象
No sign of Gretchen.
苏克雷
Sucre?
她还没来  兄弟
She ain't here yet, bro.
莎拉
Sara?
没发现
All clear.
好了  守株待兔
All right, here we go.
够了
That's far enough.
Ah... that's far enough.
对不起  丽塔
I'm sorry, Rita.
我保证不会有事的
I promise everything is going to be okay.
没错  我们都是朋友  丽塔
Yeah, we're all friends here,Rita.
完全不必担心
Don't worry about a thing.
你让冯来抓我  差点让我丧命
You know, sending Feng after me almost cost me my life,
也打破了我的计划  所以我才找你来
and it did cost me my plan, which is why you're here,
格雷琴 你得帮我找个新买家 买"锡拉"
Gretchen. You're going to help me find a new buyer for Scylla.
你跟斯科菲尔德他们通过电话呢
You've been talking to Scofield and the boys, huh?
他们怎样
Yeah, how are they?
他们很生气
Good and pissed.
他们在哪
Yeah, where are they?
唐  我不知道  我又不是他们老妈
Gee, Don, I don't know, I'm not their mother.
你不是他们老妈
You're not their mother,
但是 她和你长得很像 不是吗
but... She looks just like you. Doesn't she?
她有一双大大的蓝眼睛
She's... got those big blue eyes.
我半小时后要和他们碰面
I'm supposed to meet them in a half an hour.
给国安局打个小报告
Get ready to phone in a tip to homeland.
在哪见面
Where at?
在哪
Where?
迈克尔  开展这次行动
To perform the operation,  Michael,
大概需要 20个部门的头头签名
that would require signatures from about 20 different department heads.
唯一可行的方法 是暗中进行
The only way this is going to work is via freelancer, off the books.
我应该感谢你们
I should be thanking you.
由于你们的功劳 生活将从此改变
Okay, because of what you've done, lives are going to be changed forever.
斯科菲尔德  重新考虑了我的条件吗
Scofield, have you reconsidered my offer?
如果我把赛尔夫和"锡拉"都交给你
If I get you Self and if I can get you Scylla,
你会不会遵守之前的诺言
are you going to be able to hold up our deals?
你怎么会有这种想法
How do you intend on doing that?
我们一直努力这么做
Well, that's what we're working on.
联调局的人来了
The feds, they're here.
这是陷阱
We were set up.
把手举起来
Hands where I can see them!
杀害两名联邦探员
Killing two federal agents ought to put you back
足够判你死刑  布伦斯先生
on top of Death Row, Mr. Burrows.
我们没杀任何人 是赛尔夫在操纵
We didn't kill anyone. Self's behind this.
唐・赛尔夫 是一位称职的探员和高尚的公民
Don Self, is a decorated agent and an honorable man.
对
Yeah.
你不是第一个坐在椅子上
You wouldn't be the first guy to sit in that chair
试图蒙蔽我的人
and try to sell me a bill of goods.
你们把事情弄清时
Why weren't we halfway to Mexico
我们怎么没在去墨西哥的路上
by the time you worked things out?
-你们疏忽了  -不是
-You slipped up.  -No.
因为我们跟你一样被蒙在鼓里
Because we were in the dark just as much as you were.
布伦斯  我们清楚发生了什么事
We know what happened, Burrows.
你没有把事情联系起来
You're not putting this together.
想想"锡拉"值多少钱
Think about how much Scylla's worth.
想想赛尔夫隐蔽 这一切的尺度
Think of the lengths that Self went to to keep this thing...
一切暗中进行
to keep this thing off the books.
我们呢  我们所有人 努力完成任务
And us? Us, of all people, pulling this job off.
尸体在哪
Where are the bodies?
只要五分钟  不要想我们
For five minutes, stop thinking about us,
想想赛尔夫
and focus on Self!
我们为什么不珍视自由
Why would we jeopardize our freedom?
那是我们一直以来唯一在乎的东西
It's the only thing we've ever cared about!
费尔南多在哪
Where's Fernando?
他在路上
He's on his way.
迈克尔  我局里还有个朋友
Michael, look, I still have a friend in the Bureau
我们可以找她
we can reach out to.
也许她能找出 林肯关在什么地方
Maybe she can make some calls, see where they're holding Linc.
你打给谁
Who are you calling?
是斯科菲尔德
It's Scofield.
那就接吧
All right. So answer it.
之前有机会 我就应该打爆你的头
I should have put a bullet in your face  when I had the chance.
迈克尔  不是我陷害你
I'm not the one who set you up, Michael.
那是谁
Yeah? Who did?
迈克尔  我之前说的都是真的
You know, I meant what I said before, Michael.
我喜欢你做事的方式
I like your style. Okay?
你聪明过人
You're a smart guy.
只可惜  我比你更聪明一点
Unfortunately for you, I'm just a little bit smarter.
是吗  我们等着瞧
Yeah? We'll see about that.
听说国安局的人去了广场吧
I heard Homeland made a surprise visit to the plaza, huh?
我给你点临行建议 逃跑
Look, I'm going to give you some parting advice. Run.
带上你的同伴开始逃跑吧
Okay, get your pals and just start running.
我们得走了  迈克尔  得走了
We gotta go. Michael, we gotta go.
感谢你的帮助
I appreciate all your help, all right?
我现在要把"锡拉"卖了
I'm going to sell Scylla now.
唐  你哪也去不了
Don, you're not going anywhere.
是吗
Really? Okay.
谁是买家
Who's the buyer?
他叫怀肯
His name is Vikan.
他不是买家  他只是个中间人
And he's not a buyer. He's a conduit.
谁的中间人
A conduit to what?
我们可不是转移海洛因到这里
We're not exactly moving heroin here.
这个更特殊
It's a little bit more specialized.
世上大概有五个人
There's about five people in the world
知道"锡拉"的用途且愿意购买
who know what do with Scylla and are willing to pay for it.
行  我们走
All right. Let's go.
巴格维尔待在这里
Bagwell's staying here.
如果你动她们任何一个
You're going to find yourself captive in my negativity
我就不放过你
if you lay a hand on either one of them.
我警告过你不要惹我
I warned you not to screw me over.
你怎能这样
How could you?
我很快就回来
I'll be back very, very soon.
我保证  他不会伤害你
And I promise you, that man is not going to hurt you.
你怎能这样
How could you?
我会解决的
I'm going to fix this.
格雷琴  你真是
Wow, Gretchen, you're making friends
左右逢源啊
left and right, huh?
走吧
Now move your ass.
我们查了赛尔夫的出国鉴定
We've accessed Self's E.I.D.
找到了他试图删除的文件
We've been able to get to files he tried to delete.
我们更清楚地认识到
They're giving us a lot clearer picture
他的为人  他的企图
of who he is and what he's been up to.
很高尚  对吧
Honorable, huh?
你发现了什么
What did you find out?
一个名字  罗伯特・沃克
A name. Robert Walker.
赛尔夫打算用的新身份
The new identity Self is planning on using.
我们发现一个社保号
We found a Social Security number,
开曼的银行账号和信用卡
a bank account in the Caymans, credit cards
还有一个明早去那里的
and a flight itinerary
航班旅行指南
out of the country for tomorrow morning.
所以
So,
首先  我们向你道歉
first of all, we owe you an apology.
其次  我们抓住他时
And, second, when we finally get our hands on him,
重要的是你的帮助
it's going to be paramount to get your help.
怎么帮
How?
你的证词
Your testimony,
还有你弟弟
and the testimony of your brother
及其他人的证词
and the others against Self
来交换全部豁免权  你们就可以离开
in exchange for full immunity. You walk away.
我们已经说好的
We already had a deal.
如果你现在离开  就没有人讲清整个事件
If you walk now, there'll be no one left to tell the tale.
国安局会需要你们来掩盖事实
DHS needs you to cover its ass.
我们不能浪费时间去追捕你朋友
We can't spend our time chasing your friends.
他们得过来
They need to come in
我们才能商讨细节
so we can work out the details.
如果他们不来呢
What if they don't?
我们不敢再相信任何人了
We got a whole bunch of trust issues.
那你们只能在监狱里抑郁而终
Then, you'll all rot in a Supermax prison.
国安局会准备揭开事情真相
DHS is prepared to fly into the face of this thing
或隐瞒一切
or to bury it.
你来选择  布伦斯先生
It's your choice, Mr. Burrows.
这是你们最好的出路
This is the best you're gonna do.
迈克尔
Michael.
林肯  你在哪
Linc, where are you?
在仓库里
In the warehouse.
开扩音器
Put me on speaker.
国安局知道赛尔夫陷害了我们
Homeland knows self screwed us.
有什么消息
What do we have?
他们找到了他没有销毁掉的文件
They found a file he thought he deleted
一个国际银行账户
With an international bank account
一张离开这里的单程机票
And a one-way ticket out of here.
结束了
So it's over.
对
Yeah, well...
如果我们指证赛尔夫  就能豁免
If we testify against self, we get full immunity.
豁免什么罪
Immunity from what?
我们已经完成了
We... we did the job
他们交的任务
They hired us to do.
迈克尔  我是康拉德・达洛斯议员
Michael, senator conrad dallow.
我们有证据证明你们所说的
We have evidence that supports your claims.
我向你保证  你们没事了
I'm giving you my word your troubles are over now.
请回来  我们才能结束这一切
Please come in so we can end this
好  我决定
Okay, um, I've decided...
或者说  我认为我们应该听议员的
Rather, I think that, uh, we should hear the senator out.
而且
And, uh,
如果进展不顺
If everything goes south, then I do
我也有后备计划
Have a backup plan.
苏克雷  我希望你和莎拉一起
Sucre, I want you to go with sara
去碰面地点密切注视着
To the meeting place and get a lookout.
阿历克斯和我会确定
Alex and I are gonna make sure they don't bring
他们没有耍诈
Any surprises by doubling back
回到仓库
To the warehouse
然后跟他们去约定地点
And then following them to the rendezvous.
这是和议员见面的地点
This is where we're meeting the senator.
好吗
All right?
没问题
We'll be there.
我父亲大部分的政治生涯
You know, my father spent most of his political life...
都在伸张正义
Chasing justice.
就像某种强迫症
It was sort of an obsession.
母亲和我无法理解
And my mother and I could never understand
他为何如此轻易地
Why he would so easily
把别人的事情揽上身
Make other people's problems his own.
我想这也是她离开他的原因
And I think it's why she left him.
迈克尔  这些天
And, michael, you remind me
你不断让我想起他
more and more of him these days.
你总是把别人的事看得
The way you put everybody else's problems
比自己的还重要
Before your own.
就是说
That said...
我想让你知道
...i want you to know that,
如果和达洛斯议员的会面
if this meeting with senator dallow
没能如你所愿
doesn't go the way you want it to,
你不用担心我们的事
You don't have to worry about you and I.
没有什么
Nothing's...
没有什么能拆散我们
...nothing's gonna come between us.
对
Yeah.
一切都会好的  对吗
And everything is gonna be okay, right?
我想明白了
You know, I've figured it out.
国安局一开始对你糖衣炮弹
Dhs wined and dined you in the beginning
许你整个世界
And promised you the world,
完成之后 把你和一个傻子
And then they ultimately settled
扔到扫帚柜
On a broom closet
你就反口了
And you said nil.
格雷琴  你观察很敏锐
Gretchen, you have a real keen sense of perception.
很惊人
It's amazing.
而一切结束后
And this all ends
住塔希提岛的三层小屋  对吗
With a three-story hut in tahiti, right?
纯平电视  室外有摩托艇
Flat-screen tv, a couple jet skis outside.
唐  但你会发现
But what you're gonna find, don,
当这一切结束了
Is that when the rush is over
你不会受到任何赞誉
And you're done patting yourself on the back
也没有人给你倾诉
And there's no one left to tell the story to,
你会一如既往地孤独
You'll be just as alone as you are now.
这才是唐・赛尔夫的面目
That's who don self is.
是吗
Is that right?
你说呢
You tell me.
喂
Yeah.
拿出枪
Take out your gun.
怎么了
What's going on?
巴格维尔  你还要不要你那份钱
You want a cut or not, bagwell?
拿出枪
Take out your gun.
唐  放松点
Relax, don.
好了
All right.
瞄准她的头
Point it at her head.
唐
Don.
拉枪栓
Pull back the hammer.
唐
Don!
-我要钱  -唐
I want my money. don.
今天之内我要上飞机
And I want to be on a plane by the end of today.
否则  你和你的家人会发现
Otherwise, you and your family are gonna find out
唐・赛尔夫的真面目
Who the real don self is,
-明白吗  -是他
You understand me? that's him.
-明白了吗  -我们约好了
Do you understand me? we're set.
行了吧  是他
Okay, that's him.
3825 机场  15分钟
拜托
Please.
等我电话
I'll call you back.
东七街  1714号
1714 east seventh street.
不对啊
This can't be right.
你确定他是这样写的吗
You sure this is what he wrote down?
是这样写的
That's what it says.
是个停车场
It's a parking lot.
迈克尔为什么要选这里
Why would michael pick here?
我以为你和迈克尔
I thought you and michael
要去仓库
Were going to the warehouse.
迈克尔让我先来的
Michael sent me ahead.
怎么回事  他在哪
What's going on? where is he?
他很安全  迈克尔很安全
He's safe. michael's safe.
我们无法单独完成任务
We're not gonna be able to do this alone.
他在完成自己的任务
He's doing what he has to do,
我们也要完成自己的任务
And we have to do our part.
现在  我们上那辆公车
Right now, that's getting on that bus
离开这座城市
And getting out of the city.
现在就走
And we got to go now.
他只想让你们俩安全
He just wants you both to be safe.
走吧  必须走了
We got to go, we really got to go.
迈克尔在哪
Where is michael?
斯科菲尔德先生
Mr. scofield,
贺勃・斯坦顿
Herb stanton.
这是康拉德・达洛斯议员
This is senator conrad dallow.
我想代表美国人民
On behalf of all americans, I want
感谢你的付出
To thank you for your service.
免了  我是来给证词的
Save it. I'm here to give my testimony,
之后就和我哥哥一起离开
And then I'm leaving with my brother.
这边坐
Right over here.
好的  先生们  告诉我们你们知道的
All right, gentlemen, tell us what you know.
去往贝克斯菲尔和弗雷斯诺的
Bus 34 with service to bakersfield
34路车现在五号站台上车
And fresno now boarding in terminal five.
我们真的要离开吗
Are we really leaving?
你听到马宏说的了
You heard mahone.
这是迈克尔的主意
This is what michael wants.
没错
Yeah, right.
但如果和达洛斯的交易是合法的
Okay, but if the deal with Dallow is legit,
就没理由逃跑了  对吧
there's no reason to run, right?
迈克尔只是想保护我们
Michael's just covering the bases,
确保我们不会有麻烦
making sure that we don't run into trouble again.
对  但如果他遇到麻烦
Yes, but if he's in trouble,
会需要我们的帮助
he's going to need our help.
也许他觉得我们也不能做些什么了
Well, maybe he thinks there's nothing left for us to do.
我们现在走  就等于丢下他
If we leave now, we're leaving him behind.
我没想到唐・赛尔夫隐瞒了一切
I didn't know Don Self had it in him.
我们现在知道他是幕后黑手
Now that we know he's behind this,
形式更严峻
our situation's a lot worse.
我们别再说什么事业了
We're not talking about our careers anymore.
现在真的是牢狱之灾了
We're talking about real jail time.
我们未经国会批准
We get 15 years just for conducting
擅自组织行动  会判15年
an unauthorized operation without Congressional approval.
或者完全免除
Or not.
没必要再谈什么封锁遏制了
This doesn't have to be about containment anymore.
可以斩草除根
It could be about excision.
你意下如何  议员
You all right with that, Senator?
那让他们去吧
Then they all go.
其他人呢
Where are the others?
马宏  苏克雷  唐克雷蒂
Mahone, Sucre, Tancredi.
他们不会来
They're not coming.
林肯和我会作证  但其他人
Linc and I will testify, but the others...
我们全部豁免
Well, we all get immunity.
就这些条件
Those are the terms.
我们的证词就能把赛尔夫定罪
Our testimony alone will put Self away.
先生  我们要结束这一切
Gentleman, we can't have the others running around
就不能让他们在外逃窜
while we're trying to wrap this up.
能打他们打电话吗  叫他们过来
Can we call 'em? Can we get 'em here?
交易对象是你们所有人  这才是条件
The deal was for all of you.  Those were the terms.
不是全部人  就免谈
Without everybody, this is no deal.
听着  你们会如愿的  好吧
Listen, pal, you're gonna get what you want, all right?
你打不打电话给他们
Are you gonna call them or not?
根本没有交易  对吧  议员
Hmm, there never was a deal, was there, Senator?
我希望能给你更好的答案  迈克尔
I wish I could give you a better answer, Michael,
但唐・赛尔夫留下很多烫手山芋
but Don Self left a lot of rough edges.
我们得全部摆平
We have to smooth them out.
告诉我  他们在哪
You want to tell me where they are?
我们不会说的
It ain't gonna happen.
我能帮你抓到赛尔夫
I can get you Self.
我也能帮你拿到"锡拉"
I can still get you Scylla.
"锡拉"  我们不谈"锡拉"
Scylla? Oh, we're past Scylla.
在弄回"锡拉"和现在了结之间选择
Between getting it back and ending this now,
已经很简单了
the choice is simple.
现在就给你案件的答案  理查德
You wanted your Supermax answer, you got it, Richard.
现在走吧
Now time to go.
送苏特先生出去
Escort Mr. Sooter out.
我数到5
I'm gonna count to five.
One.
Two.
Three.
将军要见你们
You've got an appointment with General.
给你
Here you go.
在这等
Wait right here.
久违了  格雷琴
Been a long time, Gretchen.
不为将军卖命了吗
No longer working for the General?
没错
Correct.
他是谁
Who's he?
"锡拉"在我手里
I'm the guy that's holding Scylla.
有兴趣吗
You interested?
将军可给了一笔赏金
Well, the General has offered a reward for anyone
奖赏能把"锡拉"
who can return Scylla
和叛徒的人头带回去的人
along with the heads of the transgressors.
我很感激你给我机会
I appreciate you allowing me the opportunity
打击一下将军
to kick the General in the teeth.
能看看吗
Can I see it?
所有人
All of you.
苏特  拜托  我不会把你说出去
Sooter, please, I can give you cover.
省省吧  议员
Save it! Save it, Senator, save it.
将军特别交待要把你活着带过去
The General specifically asked that I bring you in alive.
快走
Just move.
你差点害死我们  议员
You were going to kill us, Senator.
是斯坦顿打的电话
It was Stanton who made that call.
30秒前的复杂形势
Look, what was extremely complicated
现在已不复存在
30 seconds ago is not so now.
6个人知道这次行动
There were six people who knew
2个还活着
about this operation. Two of them are still alive.
一个跑了  我是另一个
One is now on the run. and I'm the other.
我会守口如瓶
And I'm not saying a word.
你休想轻易脱身  议员
You're not getting off that easy, Senator.
你要帮我们
You are going to help us.
会议桌上有个手提包
There is a folder in that briefcase
包里有份文件
on the conference table.
里面记录了
It contains
这次行动的遗留问题
the last remnants of this operation.
一旦你们把它处理掉
Once you dispose of it
一切都不会发生
none of this ever existed.
这是秘密行动的
That's the saving grace
的好处
of a covert operation.
如果你们想要
If you want...
可以当作没发生过
...it never happened.
我现在要走了
I'm going to walk away now.
赶一趟航班
Catch a flight.
可能在我妻子
Maybe see my wife
睡觉前能赶到
before she goes to bed.
我只希望出去时
I only hope I don't catch a bullet in the back
不会背后来一枪
on my way out.
我很抱歉  先生们
I'm really very sorry, gentlemen.
我们努力过了
We tried.
让他走
Let him go.
林肯
Linc,
让他走
let him go.
别开枪
Don't.
让他走
Let him go.
我们现在逃吗
We running now?
你要是再这么做
I will kill you myself
我会杀了我自己的
the next time you do something like that.
马宏在哪
Where's Mahone?
他不见了
He's gone.
你把"锡拉"搞全了
Well, we can do business
我们再交易
when you get the rest of Scylla.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
这是不完整的
It's incomplete.
不完整  什么
Incom...? Wha--
玩什么把戏
Who is this clown?
-把戏  -对  把戏
Clown? Yeah, clown.
少了一个部件  小子
There's a piece missing, slick.
看  这里
Look. Here.
你好啊  唐
Hello, Don.
我想你拿了我的东西
I believe you have something that belongs to me.
过来拿吧
Come and get it.